Morning, boss.
Victim's name was Walton Parsell.
Owner of the jewelry store
found him here this morning.
Says Walton bought a woman's necklace
from her around closing time last night.
So not a robbery.
No. Local cops say there was
a jewelry store burglary
across town last month.
No signs of a break-in.
Check the surveillance footage.
What do we know about the victim?
He's a prison guard from Carson,
just outside of town.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- What?
- Oh, okay. It's in his hands.
Yeah, bit nails, not too calloused.
Blue collar job, high stress
but no heavy lifting. Prison guard.
Thought I was losing my touch
there for a second.
God forbid.
Clothes tell a different story.
Check out those formal but,
uh, comfortable boots
and the cheap business suit.
Looks, uh, looks a little like a detective.
Don't you think?
- He kinda does, doesn't he?
- Yeah.
Hey, this is not a cheap suit.
Oh, hey, hey, I'm not saying
anything about your suit.
I'm sure it's not. You're the real deal.
But this man here... he
was...he was aspirational.
He had hopes to be a lot more
than a prison guard.
- Too bad the job killed him.
- The job? How so?
Well, he worked at a prison.
That's where they keep killers.
An ex-inmate... probably our best bet.
There are a lot of stab wounds.
That's how they learn to kill in prison.
Prison shanks have points, not blades.
They use 'em to puncture
bowels, cause sepsis.
Charming. Well, the question is this...
why would you use a prison
shank outside of prison?
I'll run a check of all the ex-inmates
from Carson in the area.
It's a wedding invitation.
- Is there a dinner?
- Salmon or prime rib.
I'm in.
- Who am I sitting with?
- You're next to Cho.
Where are we with Walton Parsell?
Grew up outside of Hangtree.
Parents are dead.
No close relations nearby.
Started up at Carson on his 21st birthday.
I used his call history
to track down a girlfriend...
Shelley Dillion.
She's a hairdresser in town.
I'll take Jane and go talk to her.
Cho, you go to the prison.
Where are we with Jane's hunch
that there's an ex-con involved?
The prison sent over the
list you asked for.
Ex-Carson inmates with violent records
still living in the county.
If Jane's right
one of these guys is responsible.
It's probably shoe-leather,
but somebody should check it out.
- Take a look at that? I'm on it.
- All right.
Want a partner?
Guess not.
I need to talk to you about a murder
investigation I'm working on.
Keep walking, pig. I got nothin' for you.
Hello, dad. Good to see you, too.
- You're still here, huh? You want a beer?
- No.
'Course not.
Surprised you even know
where to find me.
Oh, I make it my business to know exactly
where you are at all times.
Really? Keepin' tabs on me, huh?
Ain't that sweet?
So you still in Sacramento?
I just need to ask you a few questions.
Procedure.
I'm talking to everyone on this
list of ex-Carson inmates.
Cops. That guard's been
dead less than a day
and you're already grasping at straws.
So you know about the case.
Know about it? Hell, boy, walking
around town ten minutes
I could tell you who the killer is.
But not cops.
They got procedures.
- Look, I... I have to know if you were...
- I get it.
No, sir, officer, I did not
kill anyone last night.
- Then tell me where you were.
- Cat and the Fiddle on Delaware.
They all remember me.
- You working?
- I get by.
Smuggling cigarettes?
Dealing Meth again?
My own flesh and blood... a lousy cop.
Makes me wanna puke.
I just don't wanna see you back in jail.
That's all.
You always were a self-righteous
little bastard.
That comes from your mom's
side of the family.
No matter how many times
I straightened you out
I never could fix you of that.
It's in the blood, I guess.
If you have nothing more to say
about Walton Parsell
thanks for your time.
I guess I'm in shock.
I feel like I'm numb, you know?
- How long had you known Walton?
- Two months.
That's pretty long for me.
And when was the last time you saw him?
Two nights ago. We had dinner out...
quick Chinese, nothing special.
He was supposed to call me last night.
But he didn't.
I thought he was done with me.
You know, like that was it.
Walton had bought a gold necklace
just before he died
and you were worried
that he was gonna leave you?
Because he was a good person?
- He wasn't your usual type, was he?
- Yeah, tell me about it.
I don't know if I'll meet another guy
like Walton.
Yes, your taste for bad boys
is a sad relic of your
childhood mistreatment.
No need to pick it back up again.
Oh, gee, thanks for the advice, Dr. Phil.
Just because you've heard it before
doesn't mean it's not good advice.
Tell us about Walton. Walton had a plan.
He wasn't floating.
He was taking night classes
at the community college...
- criminology.
- Wanted to be a detective.
Can you think of anybody who may
have wanted to hurt Walton?
No.
No, nobody.
Okay. Well, if you think of anything else
just give us a call.
I will.
Oh, Shelley, there is one more thing.
Have you ever stolen supplies
from work here?
No.
No. Of course not.
Good girl.
Walton meant well. That's for sure.
But?
Well, he had these dreams
of being a detective.
He just didn't get
that's not what we do here.
We're not detectives. We're zookeepers.
He was overzealous.
Look, I don't want my men
looking for trouble.
I want them to finish their shifts
with nobody getting hurt,
including themselves.
Did you know Walton was studying
criminology at the local college?
Yeah. That was a big part of the problem.
That school was just spurring him on.
Just last month, he told me
he was already building a case
to transfer one of the inmates
to one of those supermax facilities
getting help from one of his professors.
- Which inmate?
- Well, Walton wouldn't tell us.
It's confidential, he says.
He wanted to present his case to us
and, Warden at the next staff meeting.
Did the inmates know
what Walton was doing?
The inmates know everything...
more than me.
That's something else Walton
didn't understand.
And studies constantly show
that eyewitness identification
is wrong as often as it is right
because the human brain
is not a computer.
Can anyone tell me what day of the week
may 31st, 1976 fell on?
- Tell me quickly. You see...
- Monday.
Pardon me?
Monday. It was a Monday.
My brain is a computer.
It's a steel trap.
- A computerized steel trap...
- Professor Huff, hi.
I'm agent Lisbon. This is Patrick Jane.
We're with the CBI.
We're investigating the murder
of Walton Parsell.
Oh, I was very sorry to hear about it.
How can we help you?
We know that he was looking to transfer
an inmate at the prison, and, uh...
Yes. The inmate was involved
in extortion and racketeering
and we analyzed the legal framework
required to take action.
Did he give you the inmate's name?
Well, we deliberately don't use
real names in our conversations.
I'm sure he probably mentioned it
but I don't recall.
I'll take over from here,
if you don't mind.
Hello, class.
Memory is unreliable
because the untrained brain
has a crappy filing system.
It takes everything that happens
to you and throws it all
Willy-nilly into a big, dark closet.
When you go in there looking
for something, all you can find
are the big, obvious things
like when your mind died
or stuff that you don't really need
stuff that you're not looking for
like, uh, like the words to "Copacabana."
You can't find what you need,
but don't panic because it is still there.
Now if we may my lovely assistant
and I will help you rummage
through your magic closets.
Somewhere in there
lurks a name, so start digging
and sorting and pulling things out
and weeding through.
It may be connected to,
the way that Walton laughed
or the smell of his breath.
You just thought of something.
The inmate must have tattoos.
Walton said the guy beat up a tattooist
for spelling "Aryan" wrong.
There we go. Excellent.
Walton asked me questions
about crime in my hometown, Fontana.
Very good.
We're getting somewhere here.
Just let your mind go wherever it wants.
He may have lent you a pen.
He may have worn an ugly shirt.
No, no, he was very buttoned up
and very neat like a soldier.
Like a-a Roman soldier. A general.
Caesar.
Julius...
I know, wait...Brutus...
- Marcus. The inmate's name was Marcus.
- Marcus.
So we're looking for an inmate
with white gang tattoos
who's from Fontana whose name is Marcus.
That'll help.
Excellent work. "A"-plus.
Class dismissed. No homework.
Her name was Lola.
She was a showgirl.
Marcus Lansdale... he was a member
of the white trash lowriders from Fontana
when he shot a highway patrolman
during a routine traffic
stop ten years ago.
- Patrolman's in a wheelchair.
- Looks like Walton picked a winner.
They suspect him of running
the prison's protection racket...
protects the drug dealers from the gangs
takes care of snitches
but they can't prove any of it.
If Walton was asking questions
Lansdale probably heard about it.
Jane and I will go talk to him.
If he's involved that means
there's a hit man on the outside.
Hey Rigsby.
Jane's hunch about the
ex-Carson inmate pay off?
I checked out everyone on the list.
Nothing hinky.
All right, we need to check into
Lansdale's known associates.
- Boss, can I, talk to you for a minute?
- Sure.
- In your office.
- All right.
I've never talked to you about my father.
Sit down.
I know about your dad. I'm your boss.
Steven Robert Rigsby, convicted
of manslaughter, assault, drug dealing.
Your father was on that list, wasn't he?
I checked out his alibi.
No special treatment.
- If you wanna send someone else...
- I trust you, Rigsby.
However, if you ever come
into contact with your father
on a case, next time, you
bring somebody with you.
Yeah, okay.
You need to get a list of
Lansdale's known associates.
- Get it done by morning.
- You got it, boss.
We're here to talk to you
about Walton Parsell.
- We've read your files...
- I haven't. I'm...I'm getting to it.
I've read your file.
I know that you're running
the protection racket here at Carson
and that Walton was planning on moving you
to a higher security prison.
California law used to say that a man
sentenced to life in prison
is legally dead.
That's a fact. Legally dead.
And...
I've been a dead man for ten years.
The outside world's got no hold on me.
You think some screw poking
into my business bothers me?
Aw, you're not so tough.
There's always bigger fish.
Not in my pond.
Well, Walton wanted you transferred.
You might have ended up in a pond
with a giant pike
or snapping turtles.
I have defended myself very successfully
against charges that I am a security risk.
So whatever Parsell wanted to throw at me
would've gone the same way.
Did you know what Walton was gonna do?
Not until you told me.
Maybe one of your friends
on the outside told you.
Oh, I can take care of myself.
That's how you ought to know
I didn't kill him.
How so?
Because if I want a guard dead
you will find him in a broom closet
right here in Carson in my cellblock.
I think he's made some good points.
Marcus, it's been fun.
I got places to go and people to meet.
Personally, I think you got the cheekbones
that you can support
something really short.
I mean, it'd look great on you.
You got a great skull.
- I've always said that.
- I really wish you'd stop.
Oh, we brought a photo
as a reference.
- What?
- There.
Why didn't you tell us you
had a brother in prison?
I don't tell anyone about Marcus.
How'd you know?
Well, you share some of
the same recessive genes
same earlobes, and you both
have the same tell before you lie.
You were dating a guy who's
trying to transfer your brother.
- He ends up dead. It doesn't look good.
- Wait, wait, wait.
You think I killed him?
That's...that's crazy.
- Not really.
- Convince us.
- Where were you last night?
- Annie from the salon's bachelorette party.
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
I never would have hurt him.
But you lied to him.
Marcus knew Walton was trying
to get him transferred
so he asked me to get to know him
and see what his weaknesses are.
One day I followed Walton from Carson.
He went to a coffee shop. I went in after.
We got to talking.
We had our first date a few days later.
You thought Walton was a sucker.
He could help your brother out,
maybe get a few free meals.
What you first thought was
weakness you realized was kindness
and then you got to like the guy.
Did Walton find out about you?
No, he never found out,
and I wasn't gonna tell him.
When Marcus called me last week, I told...
You told him you couldn't do
it anymore, and he got mad.
Did he threaten you?
- You don't know what he can do.
- I think we do. Walton's dead.
Your brother couldn't
have done it from prison.
That means Walton's killer
is on the loose.
- Well...
- Well, what?
- Well, I'm not so sure. I mean, this...
- Make a statement.
Maybe we can get your brother to talk
find out who killed Walton.
No.
I'm sorry. That's... that's my brother.
I can't.
I talked to Shelley's co-workers.
Her alibi checks out.
Figures. She didn't feel
right for it anyway.
Still, she could be an accomplice.
- Where's Jane?
- Uh, first thing in the morning
he had Cho take him back to Carson.
Oh, what for? Lansdale isn't talking
and the killer's on the outside.
Whatever.
Any breaks on finding Lansdale's hit man?
I talked to Hangtree P.D.
They don't have any ideas about
a murder-for-hire candidate.
Lansdale's known associates on the outside
are a pretty small list.
His whole gang's still in jail.
I read the file from the jewelry store
burglary last month
and there's nothing there.
We need a new angle.
What is it?
There is... one angle I could try.
Well, I thought you'd be back.
But I didn't think you'd bring a gift.
We just need a moment of your time.
- Can I get you somethin' to drink?
- No.
- I wasn't talking to you.
- No, thank you.
You get on that yet?
I warned her you'd be crude.
Couldn't close the deal, huh?
Look, we need your help finding
the killer of Walton Parsell.
Yeah, you said you could find
the killer in ten minutes.
If I wanted to do that, but why
would I wanna do that?
To show me you can.
Show me you're not just full of big talk.
Well, the least you could do is ask nice.
I know you know how to ask nice.
Please, dad. I need your help.
All right. We need to find a woman
by the name of Rocket.
Old flame of mine.
She knows everything
that goes on in Hangtree.
- Rocket? Real name?
- Elaine Hamilton.
Got an address?
Well, I don't know where she sleeps
but I know where she lives...
this jailbird bar in town.
Can you take us to her?
Yeah, I can do that.
Just give me a second. I'll get my keys.
"He was trying to, uh, transfer Lansdale?"
"See, that's Walton for you."
"Meant well, but naive."
Lansdale sounds like a
good target for transfer.
Lansdale is the muscle at Carson.
Nobody's gonna talk to Walton.
They don't wanna find themselves
on the bad end of Lansdale's knife.
He did his own dirty work?
He who holds the knife
gets the respect from the guys.
You wanna stay on top,
you gotta back it up.
This is great. Reality tv at its finest.
Everything that happens in cellblock "c"
is right here on these monitors.
Lansdale's too hard-core for a small place.
You didn't think about transfer yourself?
We're guards, not supermen.
Having a shark like Lansdale in the tank
keeps all these guys in line.
He does your job for you. That's nice.
So you disapproved of Walton
going after Lansdale.
I didn't have any knowledge of that...
Walton's agenda.
That would be supposition.
Okay.
Oh, you see these two?
They're about to punch each other.
Look at the way their shoulders are set.
It's very primal.
So are we done here? I got work to do.
Jane, you have anything else?
Oh! There they go.
Look, look, look, look. Fight.
We got a fight in northwest hallway "B."
Somebody break it up.
Okay, I'm on my way.
Lock the... lock the hallway down.
Jane, unless you have something,
we need to get out of here.
No, you go.
I'll...I'll get a ride home somehow.
- This is way too good.
- All right.
Way too good.
- You gonna be here all day?
- Oh, there you are.
I don't wanna scare you, but, uh...
I did some time myself once.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
Anyway, when I was inside
there were prisoners with privileges.
- What do you call those... trustees?
- Yeah.
- You have some here?
- Yeah, we have a few.
I'd like to talk to them.
Okay. Let's go.
Those guys in the blue...
that's trustees from cellblock "c."
That's Walton's block.
The bald man with the tattoo...
he got long left on his sentence?
Velasquez. Down to his last year.
I'll take him.
Jorge! Over here.
Let's take two. Keep 'em honest.
Uh... the guy on the other end.
Other side of the table.
Nick Monaco. Another short-timer.
He's not a murderer, is he?
No, Nicky's a second-story man.
A thief. Got clean hands.
Him, too.
Nicky! Over here.
This is the place all right.
- You wait here. I'll go get her.
- No, we'll get her.
You two go walking in there looking like
the cop family Robinson
the joint will clear out
and you'll never find Rocket.
Okay. You're not back in two minutes,
we're coming in.
You got it, officer.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. 'Sup, Peckerwoods?
You know that game that kids play...
"My dad can beat up your dad"?
No one ever played that with me.
He's a...
- Character.
- Yep.
Maybe this will bring you
two closer together.
Don't hold your breath.
Hey, put it down!
You get her. I'm going in.
Stop!
So bad now... lower your weapon now!
- Get on outta here, boy.
- I'm a cop. Everybody stay calm.
He's got a knife. Yeah, I can see that.
What the hell's going on in here?
Seems Andy over here was a little mad
over the last time we crossed paths.
Wanted to fistfight,
only I don't do fistfights.
- A waste of time. Right, Andy?
- Let me go. Please?
Just put the knife down!
Let me handle this.
The hell with that.
Dad, nobody needs to get cut
and nobody needs to get shot.
Just put the knife down.
Guess Old Andy here ain't gonna be
taking any more pokes at me.
That's for sure.
You, get outta here.
Your turn.
Put the gun away,
and we'll call this a wash.
Better.
Let's go.
What are you trying to do, embarrass me?
Never get between me
and my business again.
I just saved your life in there.
What, that clown?
He wasn't gonna pull the trigger.
Really? And how'd you know?
Weakness, son.
Weakness. Lives in the eyes.
Meet Rocket.
She's faster than she looks.
- What the hell, Rigs?
- I told you to play nice.
You know something about a prison guard
getting killed in town?
No. No, sir, I do not.
If I'm lyin', I'm dyin'.
Tell 'em.
Butch Carwin.
Came into the bar last night.
Flashed a wad of cash
that would choke a mule.
Said he dropped some prison
guard for the dough.
Where can we find Carwin?
Well, he owns some land out
near the quarry off route 23.
All right. Thanks for your assistance.
You some kind of V.I.P. or somethin'?
Something. You boys can relax.
I'm an ex-con myself.
Writing wolf tickets,
talking out your neck. I'm hip.
- Whatever you say, pal.
- Okay.
That's an interesting tattoo.
Looks fresh. You just get that?
Yeah. My cousin just landed
in here for drugs.
- Nice.
- He's a real artist.
Well, maybe Nick could use his services.
Not me. I'm not into all that ink.
Old school. I get it.
I take care of myself. So what?
Nothing wrong with that.
- What's through there?
- It's a loading bay for the laundry.
Let's go take a look, shall we?
Do the laundry for every hotel
and restaurant in Hangtree.
Wow. Must keep the prisoners very busy.
Three shifts a day.
Yeah, all us trustees work as supervisors
here in the laundry.
Must know the movers and shakers
around here, huh?
Guys like Lansdale.
I know to mind my own business.
You know, you seem like a smart guy.
- Don't be an idiot.
- Excuse me?
If you know something
maybe about Lansdale
and his reign of terror
then tell me.
I can get your sentence shortened.
Listen here.
I got six months left in this joint
and then I'm free.
I'd like to spend those
six months unstabbed.
I get it. I've been down.
Snitches get stitches.
Oh, see, that's a popular misconception.
The stitches are for live people.
Got it.
Is that him?
Mask doesn't help
but yeah, I think so.
Looks like butch Carwin's got himself
a good old-fashioned meth lab.
And he's armed.
That's probable cause.
We can take him in right now.
- We should call for backup.
- No need. This is gonna be easy.
You don't need to prove
anything to anyone.
Your father is the last person in the world
you should be trying to impress.
You're a good person in spite of him.
You don't owe him anything.
You got me wrong.
I don't give a damn about my dad.
I'm just saying we can take
Carwin down now, no problem.
CBI! Down to the ground, Carwin!
Get down!
- On the ground!
- Who's there?
- Who's there? I can't see anything, man!
- I'll pass. Get down on the ground now!
Okay, okay. Son of a bitch.
Facedown on the ground!
Arms out to the side now.
Pretty good trick.
Yep. Always worked on my dad.
We've got you for production
of methamphetamine and illegal weapons.
Who knows what else we're gonna find?
I'm just no damn good. That's the truth.
You recognize this man?
I might have done a piece
of time with a fella like that once.
Lansdale.
What about this man?
Oh, him I don't know. Looks like a cop.
He's the man you killed
for Marcus Lansdale.
Okay, hold up. I did what now?
Murder for hire. It's a capital crime.
You finger Lansdale, you'll just
go to jail for a long time.
Okay, look, I don't know
who's telling you what
but I've never seen that fella in my life.
Why don't you tell me where
you were two nights ago?
Oh, I was cooking up meth.
Hang tight, Butch.
It's gonna be a long day.
- Hello?
- Lisbon, it's Jane.
I'm in jail. Come join me.
You're still in Carson? Why?
Uh... I'm catching the killer, of course.
Look, we've got a pretty good
suspect in holding here.
You would know that if
you answered your phone.
These places aren't exactly
built for their reception.
Anyway, trust me, Lisbon.
"Get your car keys. Get in your car."
And...
Lisbon? Yeah.
"What's this about?"
Uh, the gentleman with
the shaking leg right there.
Tomas. Come on.
Aw, man.
Looks like heroin.
Uh, and I think if you
check the water fountain
you might find, uh...
Huh?
Bingo.
- It's not mine, man.
- I'm sure it's not. Let's go. Let's go.
I'm so sure. Let's go. Let's go.
You had me drive all the way out here
to watch you bust a drug dealer?
It wasn't a bust.
I just had to check to see
if my informant's info was good.
Informant?
Yeah, I got one of the prisoners talking.
Gonna give us Lansdale.
- Which prisoner did you get talking?
- Nick, the thief.
Yeah. I did the old razzle-dazzle on him.
It was very cop.
He's ready to make a statement
as soon as we can draw up
the paperwork to get him outta here.
Nobody likes a snitch.
Let's get him outta here.
Take it.
The drug bust in the cafeteria...
I know who talked.
- Oh, yeah? Who?
- Nick, the thief.
Nick?
Cop said he's giving you up next.
No, he's not. You get me a knife.
Just before lights out. You be ready.
Lab techs just finished
going through the stuff we
seized from Carwin.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. It's turning out
to be a pretty nice case.
Meth lab but a garage
full of stolen stereos
and about 600 cartons
of untaxed cigarettes.
- Looks like your dad came through for once.
- Wait. What?
- I said it looks like your dad...
- Untaxed cigarettes?
- Yeah? So?
- Cover for me. I gotta go.
You know?
- Kind of busy here, boy.
- Your lead was crap.
Butch Carwin didn't kill that guard
but he is smuggling cigarettes, like you.
- That's a weird coincidence, huh?
- I think I'll freshen this up.
Yeah, I think you should.
She lied for you to help take out a rival.
Only thing a cop's ever good for...
getting rid of the competition.
Besides, you got yourself a nice, big bust
for you and the redhead.
Everybody's happy.
You used me.
Hey, what's family for?
- You know? I think your mom...
- Don't talk about my mom.
Shut up. You shut up!
Well, now...
Thinking that maybe taking a punch
at the old man will fix you up right?
Give you some inner peace?
But before you swing,
you remember what I said before.
I don't do fistfights.
Come ahead, son.
"Locking up in 15 minutes, gentlemen."
Kill that snitch.
Nick, I'm coming for you.
Drop the knife, Lansdale.
Don't make me have to
pepper-spray your ass.
You know the drill.
This enough to send him to supermax?
I gotta say Walton would have liked
to have seen this.
- Don't worry. We'll pack your bags for you.
- Yeah? Well, you can all go to hell.
And that goes double for Nick.
It's all over this place that
he was the one snitching on me.
Get him outta here.
I know somebody's gonna get that rat!
Take him outta here.
Lock the cellblock down.
You better move Nick to an isolation unit.
We put him in the laundry room
on the night shift. Let's go.
Time's up, Nicky.
Nick?
Where'd Nick go?
You seen Nick?
- He was just at the desk.
- Well, he's not now.
We've got a missing convict.
Put us on lockdown.
"Lockdown in cell block C.
Inmate missing."
- Is it a rabbit?
- Yeah, it's a rabbit.
Rabbit dancing?
Rabbits don't dance.
Cho, got our laundry truck.
Guys, light it up.
Sir, I'm gonna need you to step out
of the vehicle.
Olly, olly, oxen free!
Son of bitch!
I had to run.
You made everyone think I was a snitch.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry about that.
My bad, but I just thought
it was the best way
for you to show us how you
sneak in and out of prison.
Just like you did the night
you killed Walton.
I got nothin' to say.
Well, we have ways of making you talk.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- Keeping warm.
You burn my whole stash?
Yup.
Hard-core.
I do you. You do me,
and that's the way it should be.
So does that make us even?
No.
All right, son.
Just this once.
I'll give you a fair chance.
Too much damn cop in you, boy.
We're not done yet.
Should've used the knife.
See you around, son.
The laundry truck driver
is in the other room
singing like a bird.
Save us some time and talk
and we'll move you to the east coast
where nobody knows you're a snitch.
I never snitched.
This guy here made that up.
Oh, well, have fun explaining that
to the boys on the cellblock.
What the hell. I'm cooked, right?
I was supposed to get out in six months.
I wanted to have something waiting for me.
So I found that jewelry store in town.
I promised that driver a share
if he'd sneak me out.
"Yes, his poor taste in jewelry
was a very early clue."
So I robbed the place.
It went smooth.
So I figure, let's do another one.
And that's when you ran into Walton.
Kid didn't have to be a hero.
"He could've just left it alone."
"That's just how he was, you know?"
"He had to try and do the right thing."
Thought I got away clean.
Well, I figured someone that was
getting in and out of prison
must have the trust of the
guards, hence a trustee
and the laundry...
well, that's just the smartest way out.
That could have been any one of us.
Yes, but you and Jorge stood out.
That's why I chose you both.
His tattoo was far better work
than the average prison
work you see, and fresh.
Then he mentioned his cousin,
the artist, which leaves you
and your perfectly manicured digits.
There's not a nail salon
in prison, is there?
I like to look right.
I'm old school.
I never killed anyone on any of my jobs.
I never had to.
I was too good to need violence.
But still, you took a knife with you.
Someone stands in front of you
gonna take away everything
you gotta put him down.
I mean, right or wrong, you put him down.
You get that.
Don't you?
Hey.
Hey. What happened to you tonight?
- Something with your dad?
- Yeah.
I was gonna make coffee.
Do you wanna go to the shop
down the street, talk about it?
No, I'm fine.
I'm better than fine, actually.
All right.
Wait. There's just one more thing.
I'm sorry, but I'm not gonna be
at your wedding.
That's too bad.
You have something else
planned that day?
No. You see, the problem is...
I'm still in love with you.
- You can't...
- Hold on.
I'm not trying to win you back.
You're marrying a good man.
That's not gonna change.
But neither am I.
This whole thing where we pretend
that we're just friends...
it...it doesn't work.
I don't know if it will work
but I know one thing.
I can't watch you marry another man.
All right.
You have a good day...
And a good life.